<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Autoencoder on Isaac Changhau</title>
    <link>https://isaacchanghau.github.io/tags/autoencoder/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Autoencoder on Isaac Changhau</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 14:20:36 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://isaacchanghau.github.io/tags/autoencoder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Variational Autoencoders Explained</title>
      <link>https://isaacchanghau.github.io/post/vae_explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 14:20:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacchanghau.github.io/post/vae_explained/</guid>
      <description>Note: This blog article is borrowed from kevin frans blog · Variational Autoencoders Explained.
In my previous post about generative adversarial networks, I went over a simple method to training a network that could generate realistic-looking images.
However, there were a couple of downsides to using a plain GAN.
First, the images are generated off some arbitrary noise. If you wanted to generate a picture with specific features, there&amp;rsquo;s no way of determining which initial noise values would produce that picture, other than searching over the entire distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autoencoder and Sparsity</title>
      <link>https://isaacchanghau.github.io/post/autoencoder_and_sparsity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacchanghau.github.io/post/autoencoder_and_sparsity/</guid>
      <description>The article is excerpted from Andrew Ng&amp;rsquo;s CS294A Lecture notes: Sparse Autoencoder with some personal understanding. Before going through this article, you would better get some information from the Backpropagation Algorithm.
Suppose we have only unlabeled training examples set $\{x^{(1)},x^{(2)},x^{(3)},\dots\}$, where $x^{(i)}\in\mathbb{R}^{n}$. An autoencoder neural network is an unsupervised learning algorithm that applies backpropagation, setting the target values to be equal to the inputs. i.e., it uses $y^{(i)}=x^{(i)}$. Below is an autoencoder: The autoencoder tries to learn a function $h_{W,b}(x)\approx x$.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>