<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Relation-representation on Isaac Changhau</title>
    <link>https://isaacchanghau.github.io/tags/relation-representation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Relation-representation on Isaac Changhau</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://isaacchanghau.github.io/tags/relation-representation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PTransE -- Modeling Relation Paths for Representation Learning of Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://isaacchanghau.github.io/post/ptranse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacchanghau.github.io/post/ptranse/</guid>
      <description>It is a summary of the paper Modeling Relation Paths for Representation Learning of Knowledge Bases (PTransE). PTransE is a novel extension of TransE, which is a path-based representation learning model, to model relation paths for representation learning of knowledge bases. The authors argue that multiple-step relation paths also contain rich inference patterns between entities, thus, PTransE also considers relation paths as translations between entities for representation learning, and addresses two key challenges:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TransX: Embedding Entities and Relationships of Multi-relational Data</title>
      <link>https://isaacchanghau.github.io/post/transx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacchanghau.github.io/post/transx/</guid>
      <description>It is a summary of several papers about embedding entities and relationships of multi-relational knowledge database, while each paper contains one kind of specific method. Generally, the set of methods are called TransX. Here, I only describe the general idea and mathematical process of each method, for more information about those methods in parameters setting, experiment results and discussion, you can directly read the original papers through the links I provide.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>